Guide to the Dean Sakamoto Collection of Yale School of Architecture Exhibition Publications
Yale University Arts Library
Dean Sakamoto Collection of Yale School of Architecture Exhibition Publications
1999-2011
ART 15
Yale University Arts Library
1.25
(1 box)
The collection contains 36 selected publications which were published during Dean Sakamoto's tenure as Director of Exhibitions for the Yale School of Architecture.
Sakamoto, Dean
Yale University. School of Architecture
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Dean Sakamoto, 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Dean Sakamoto is a practicing architect and a critic at the Yale School of Architecture. He was Director of Exhibitions for the School's gallery from 1999 to 2011.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains 36 selected publications which were published during Dean Sakamoto's tenure as Director of Exhibitions for the Yale School of Architecture.
Arrangement
Arranged in reverse chronological order.
Architecture -- Exhibitions
- Box listing
  - Kevin Roche: Architecture as Environment, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2011. (Box 1)
  - The Structure of Light: Richard Kelly and the Illumination of Modern Architecture, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2010. (Box 1)
  - Eero Saarinen: Shaping the Future, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2010. (Box 1)
  - What We Learned: The Yale Las Vegas Studio and the Work of Venturi Scott Brown & Associates, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2009. (Box 1)
  - The Green House: New Directions in Sustainable Architecture & Design, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2009. (Box 1)
  - Worlds Away, New Suburban Landscapes, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2009. (Box 1)
  - Model City: Buildings and Projects by Paul Rudolph for Yale and New Haven, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2008. (Box 1)
  - Hawaiian Modern: The Architecture of Vladimir Ossipoff, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2008. (Box 1)
  - Painting the Glass House, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2008. (Box 1)
  - Ecology. Design. Synergy, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2007. (Box 1)
  - A Field Guide to Sprawl, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2007. (Box 1)
  - UNStudio: Evolution of Space, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2007. (Box 1)
  - Some Assembly Required: Contemporary Prefabricated Houses, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2006. (Box 1)
  - Team 10: A Utopia of the Present, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2006. (Box 1)
  - Transcending Type, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2006. (Box 1)
  - Prairie Skyscraper: Frank Lloyd Wright's Price Tower, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2005. (Box 1)
  - Ant Farm: 1968-78, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2005. (Box 1)
  - Jean Prouve: A Tropical House, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2005. (Box 1)
  - Light Structures: The Work of Jorg Schlaich and Rudolf Bergermann, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2005. (Box 1)
  - PSFS: Nothing More Modern, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2004. (Box 1)
  - Big and Green: Toward Sustainable Architecture in the 21st Century, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2004. (Box 1)
  - Robert Damora: 70 Years of Total Architecture, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2003. (Box 1)
  - Intricacy, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2003. (Box 1)
  - MATTER: The Work of Todd Williams and Billie Tsien, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2003. (Box 1)
  - Eisenman/Krier: Two Ideologies, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2002. (Box 1)
  - 3D City: Studies in Density, recent work by MVRDV, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2002. (Box 1)
  - Zaha Hadid Laboratory, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2002. (Box 1)
  - Architecture or Revolution, Charles Moore and Yale in the Late 1960s, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2001. (Box 1)
  - New Blue: Recent Work of Graduates of Yale School of Architecture, 1978-1998, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2001. (Box 1)
  - Cities and Buildings, Koetter Kim & Associates, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2001. (Box 1)
  - 2 Views of Eero Saarinen, The Architectural Photography of Balthazar Korab and Ezra Stoller, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2001. (Box 1)
  - Saving Corporate Modernism: Three Landmark Buildings by Gordon Bunshaft of Skidmore Owings & Merrill, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2001. (Box 1)
  - Cesar Pelli, Building Designs 1965-2000, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 2000. (Box 1)
  - The Work of Daniel Libeskind, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 1999. (Box 1)
  - Re-Connections: The Work of the Eames Office, exhibition catalog with Nina Rappaport and David Reinfurt. [New Haven, CT]: Yale University School of Architecture, 1999. (Box 1)